CARLOS NETO

DEVOPS ENGINEER

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/c-neto/

https://github.com/augustoliks

Prazil - São Paulo

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Self-learning and Ownership mindset IT professional, with tech skills in Programming, Documentation, and DevOps.

It is a Python programming specialist, experienced in Amazon Web Services, focused on system provisioning, automation scripts, and managing logs pipelines and observability stacks.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

DevOps Engineer

Trustly Inc. | Online Banking Payments

Movember 2021 - Current

Remote

DevOps Engineer focused on Cloud infrastructure demands. Responsible for automation, log pipelines, and Cloud components configuration in a world system-wide online banking platform.

Main tasks carried out:

- Automation scripts with Python and Bash;
- OpenSearch cluster management (RBAC, ISM, templates);
- Logstash log pipelines (Enriching, Grok);
- AWS resources analysis and configuration;
- Kubernetes operation, troubleshooting, and development;
- Knowledge Base documentation.

Software Developer

Fotosensores | Speed Camera Systems

April. 2018 - October. 2021

• On-site

Software Developer focused on In-House infrastructure demands. Responsible for microservices development, system provisioning, and observability in a regional system-wide Speed Camera System.

Main tasks carried out:

- Python microservices, scripts, and integrations;
- GitLab CI/CD pipelines;
- Observability and monitoring with Zabbix, Prometheus, and Grafana;
- Linux Servers management and packing (Red Hat based);
- Knowledge Base documentation.

PROJECTS

- **SFTP Cluster (Trustly Inc.)**: High available SFTP server with users setup provisioned by Ansible and deployment over Kubernetes;
- OpenSearch RBAC (Trustly Inc.): RBAC roles provisioned by OpenSearch Security Plugin based on Principle of Least Privilege;
- Image Transmissions Module (Fotosensores): Speed camera systems module to send vehicle images with integrity and cryptography built;
- Speed Camera Monitoring System (Fotosensores): Web system focused on speed camera system components observability.

EDUCATION

Analisys and Development System (High-Education)

FATEC - São José dos Campos

July 2016 - July 2019

Computer Network (Full-Certified)
ETEC - Cônego José Bento

february 2016 - July 2017

Industrial Automation (Full-Certified)

ITJ - Instituto de Tecnologia de Jacareí

February 2013 - December 2015

- GitLab Certified Associate Gitlab Inc;
- Python Formation Certified Alura;
- Fluent Pyhon Book.

SKILLS

Programming

Python Bash

Cloud

AWS

• CI/CD and GitOps

GitLab Github TravisCI

134 11 1

ArgoCD

Observability and Monitoring

Grafana Zabbix Prometheus Loki
Logstash Rsyslog Promtail

Containers

Kubernetes Docker Podman

• Infrastructure as a Code

Ansible Terraform

Messaging and Reverse Proxy

RabbitMQ ZeroMQ Redis

NGINX Traefik